Guide to the Czesław Miłosz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1929-1999; Series IX; 11.47; (30 boxes)
  - Photocopies of Articles
    - English
      - Articles by Czesław Miłosz, undated (Box 228, Folder 3461-3463)
      - Articles about Czesław Miłosz, undated (Box 229, Folder 3464-3468)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 229, Folder 3469-3473)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 230, Folder 3474-3486)
    - French
      - Articles by and about Czesław Miłosz, undated (Box 231, Folder 3487-3488)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 231, Folder 3489-3490)
    - Other languages
      - Articles by and about Czesław Miłosz, undated (Box 231, Folder 3491-3496)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 232, Folder 3497-3500)
  - Printed volumes
    - Serials
      - Aidai, 1953 (Box 233, Folder 3501)
      - L'art contemporain, 1929 (Box 233)
      - Artes, 1981 (Box 233, Folder 3502)
      - Barykada wolności, 1942 (Box 233, Folder 3503)
      - Biuletyn informacyjny, 1941-1942 (Box 233, Folder 3504-3505)
      - Bulletin lithuanien, 1953 (Box 233, Folder 3506)
      - Christian order, 1980 (Box 233, Folder 3507)
      - Co czytać, 1984 (Box 233, Folder 3508)
      - Committee in support of Solidarity, 1987 (Box 233, Folder 3509)
      - Dnia na dzień, 1942 (Box 233, Folder 3510)
      - Druk, 1933
      - Informator kulturalny, 1980 (Box 233, Folder 3511)
      - Jedność, 1980 (Box 233, Folder 3512)
      - Journal des poètes, 1950-1957
      - Kolumna literacka, 1935
      - Ku Polsce szklanych domów, 1936
      - Kuźnica, 1945 (Box 233, Folder 3513)
      - Lindisfarne letter, 1982 (Box 233, Folder 3514)
      - Liste des deutschfeindlichen, schädlichen und unerwünschten polnischen Schrifttums, 1940 (Box 233, Folder 3515)
      - Literatura, 1980 (Box 233, Folder 3516)
      - Merkuriusz polski, 1956-1957 (Box 233, Folder 3517)
      - Mr. Cogito, 1988 (Box 233, Folder 3518)
      - Myśl państwowa, 1942 (Box 233, Folder 3519)
      - Nasze myśli, 1979 (Box 233, Folder 3520)
      - Naujoji romuva, 1940 (Box 233, Folder 3521)
      - Nowa kwadryga, 1937 (Box 233, Folder 3522)
      - Odra, 1981 (Box 233, Folder 3523-3524)
      - Piony, 1932
      - Poetry chronicle, 1989 (Box 234, Folder 3525)
      - Poezja, 1980 (Box 234, Folder 3526)
      - Polska odrodzona, 1942 (Box 234, Folder 3527)
      - Polska zbrojna moralnie, 1942 (Box 234, Folder 3528)
      - Poprostu, 1935
      - Powściągliwość i praca, 1986
      - Prospettive nel mondo, 1980 (Box 234, Folder 3529)
      - Razem, 1932
      - Rzeczpospolita polska, 1941 (Box 234, Folder 3530)
      - Wiadomości polskie, 1941 (Box 234, Folder 3531)
      - Wilcze Kły, 1932
      - Włóczęga, 1933
      - Wolna polska, 1942 (Box 234, Folder 3532)
      - Z dziejów, 1907 (Box 234, Folder 3533)
    - Monographs
      - Akademicki Klub Włóczęgów "Kajman," Wyprawa kajakowa Śladami odysa, 1981 (Box 235, Folder 3534)
      - Andruszkiewicz, Franciszek, various titles, 1928-1935 (Box 235, Folder 3535)
      - Apenszlak, Jacob and Moshe Polakiewicz, Armed resistance of the Jews in Poland, 1944 (Box 235, Folder 3536)
      - Bakun, Teodora, Rzeźba, undated (Box 235, Folder 3537)
      - De, Dipak, Concept of literature, 1981 (Box 235, Folder 3538)
      - Duncan, Robert, A seventeenth century suite in homage to the metaphysical genius in English poetry, 1971-1973 (Box 235, Folder 3539)
      - Dzień, Mirosław, Cierpliwość, 1998 (Box 235, Folder 3540)
      - Gołębiewska, Wanda, Na mojej ulicy, 1999 (Box 235, Folder 3541)
      - Grzeszczyk, Maria and Władysław, various titles, 1983 (Box 235, Folder 3542)
      - Jankiewicz, Leo, Głód, 1992 (Box 235, Folder 3543)
      - Jankowska, Bożena, 1997 (Box 235, Folder 3544)
      - Jarecka, Danuta, 1995 (Box 235, Folder 3545)
      - Koehler, Krzysztof, Wiersze, 1990 (Box 235, Folder 3546)
      - Lawson, JonArno, Love is an observant traveller, 1997 (Box 235, Folder 3547)
      - Meckseper, Friedrich, The Nobel prizes, 1983 (Box 235, Folder 3548)
      - Podgórski, Juliusz, Wycinki z życia, 1999 (Box 235, Folder 3549)
      - Sikora, Jerzy, Jestem złodziejem światła, 1995 (Box 236, Folder 3550)
      - Słowacki, Juliusz, Powinszowanie nowego roku, 1987 (Box 236, Folder 3551)
      - Słowacki, Juliusz, Uspokojenie, 1978 (Box 236, Folder 3552)
      - Stefanik, Ernest and Cis (editors), Encircled by an alphabet, 1975 (Box 236, Folder 3553)
      - Szoka, Elbieta and Joe W. Bratcher III (editors), The dirty goat, 1989 (Box 236, Folder 3554)
      - Topolski, Feliks, Confessions of a congress delegate, 1949 (Box 236, Folder 3555)
      - University of California, Berkeley, The Nobel tradition at Berkeley, 1984 (Box 236, Folder 3556)
      - Whalen, Michael Griffin, John Paull II: Superpope, 1989 (Box 236, Folder 3557)
      - Exhibit catalogs, 1981-1988 (Box 236, Folder 3558-3560)
- Oversize Papers
  - Series I -- Antoniszczak, Richard, 1982-1984 (Box 237, Folder 3561)
  - Series I -- Rannit, Aleksis, undated (Box 237, Folder 3562)
  - Series I -- Other papers found in correspondence, undated (Box 237, Folder 3563)
  - Series II-- Poetry -- Collected volumes -- Book jackets, 1978-1988, undated (Box 237, Folder 3564)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Major Works in Prose -- Book jackets, 1953-1986, undated (Box 237, Folder 3565)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Essays -- "Braterski rozmówca," printed version, 1995 (Box 237, Folder 3566)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Essays -- "Brognart: Moja opowieść przy szklance," background material, 1952 (Box 237, Folder 3567)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Essays -- "Nacjonalizm i Bałtowie," printed version, 1993 (Box 237, Folder 3568)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Essays -- Portrait of Poland, compiled by Jan Krok-Paszkowski (preface by Miłosz), proof, 1982 (Box 237, Folder 3569)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Essays -- "L'amour absolu," printed version, 1956 (Box 237, Folder 3570)
  - Series II -- Prose -- Major Works in Prose -- Land of Ulro, proofs, 1984 (Box 238, Folder 3571)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Fiut, Aleksander, "Jesteśmy w momencie przejściowym," printed version, 1989 June 22 (Box 239, Folder 3572)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Kasprzyk, Krzysztof W., "Poeta nie może zamilknąć," printed version, 1980 (Box 239, Folder 3573)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Kowalska, Irena, "Patrzę na świat oczami człowieka wychowanego ...," printed version, 1980 (Box 239, Folder 3574)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Łęcka, Gabriela, "W Polsce, czyli wszędzie," printed version, 1993 (Box 239, Folder 3575)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Morawiec, Elżbieta, "Nie chcę być zbyt głęboki," printed version, 1981 (Box 239, Folder 3576)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Rogers, Kim Lacy, "An interview with Czeslaw Milosz: Poetry, Poland and the past," printed version, 1981 (Box 239, Folder 3577)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Sawicka, Elżbieta, Newspaper reports, printed versions, 1992 (Box 239, Folder 3578)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- Szyma, Tadeusz, "Trudnie Dziedzictwo," printed version, 1990 June 3 (Box 239, Folder 3579)
  - Series III, -- Interviews of Milosz -- Życie Akademickie, printed version, 1954 (Box 239, Folder 3580)
  - Series III -- Interviews of Milosz -- "Le message rentré d'Einstein" (Sorbonne), printed version, 1983 (Box 239, Folder 3581)
  - Series VI -- Drawings, 1988 (Box 239, Folder 3582)
  - Series V -- Other Professional Papers -- Awards, certificates, and diplomas, 1978-1986 (Box 240, Folder 3583-3587)
  - Series V -- Other Professional Papers -- Medals, 1975-1983, undated (Box 241, Folder 3588-3594)
  - Series VII -- At the Centre du Dialogue, 1970s (Box 242, Folder 3595)
  - Series VII -- In Poland, 1981 (Box 242, Folder 3596-3597)
  - Series VII -- Miscellanea, 1984 (Box 242, Folder 3598)
  - Series VII -- Portraits, 1980s (Box 242, Folder 3599)
  - Series VII -- Tomb of Syruć family, undated (Box 242, Folder 3600)
  - Series VII -- Lithuanian landscapes and buildings (in Apytalaukis and Šeteniai), undated (Box 242, Folder 3601-3602)
  - Series VII -- Vilnius, Lithuania, undated (Box 242, Folder 3603)
  - Series VIII -- General Writings of Others -- Andruszkiewicz, Franciszek, 1928-1947 (Box 243, Folder 3604)
  - Series IX -- Writings of Czesław Miłosz, 1945-1986 (Box 243, Folder 3605-3614)
  - Series IX -- Writings of Czesław Miłosz, 1932-1987 (Box 244, Folder 3615-3620)
  - Series IX -- Writings of Czesław Miłosz, 1988-1997, undated (Box 245, Folder 3621-3626)
  - Series IX -- General Clippings, 1944-1969 (Box 246, Folder 3627-3641)
  - Series IX -- General Clippings, 1970-1979 (Box 247, Folder 3642-3646)
  - Series IX -- General Clippings, 1980 (Box 248, Folder 3647-3655)
  - Series IX -- General Clippings, 1981 (Box 249, Folder 3656-3663)
  - Series IX -- General Clippings, 1982-1986 (Box 250, Folder 3664-3673)
  - Series IX -- General Clippings, 1987-1999, undated (Box 251, Folder 3674-3685)
  - Series IX -- Ephemera, 1950s-1989, undated (Box 252, Folder 3686-3690)
  - Series IX -- Photocopies of Articles -- Miscellanea in English, undated (Box 252, Folder 3691)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- L'art contemporain, 1929 (Box 253, Folder 3692)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Druk, 1933 (Box 253, Folder 3693)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Journal des poètes, 1950-1957 (Box 253, Folder 3694-3695)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Kolumna Literacka, 1935 (Box 253, Folder 3696)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Ku Polsce szklanych domów, 1936 (Box 253, Folder 3697)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Piony, 1932 (Box 253, Folder 3698)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Poprostu, 1935 (Box 253, Folder 3699)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Powściągliwość i praca, 1986 (Box 253, Folder 3700)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Razem, 1932 (Box 253, Folder 3701)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Wilcze Kły, 1932 (Box 253, Folder 3702)
  - Series IX -- Printed volumes -- Serials -- Włóczęga, 1933 (Box 253, Folder 3703)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Box 1, folder 1 (Box 254, Folder 3704)
  - Box 1, folder 14 (Box 254, Folder 3705)
  - Box 1, folder 36 (Box 254, Folder 3706)
  - Box 1, folder 48 (Box 254, Folder 3707)
  - Box 2, folder 52 (Box 254, Folder 3708)
  - Box 2, folder 64 (Box 254, Folder 3709)
  - Box 2, folder 66 (Box 254, Folder 3710)
  - Box 2, folder 73 (Box 254, Folder 3711)
  - Box 3, folder 90 (Box 254, Folder 3712)
  - Box 7, folder 146 (Box 254, Folder 3713)
  - Box 8, folder 165 (Box 254, Folder 3714)
  - Box 16, folders 291-295 (Box 254, Folder 3715)
  - Box 18, folders 316-322 (Box 254, Folder 3716)
  - Box 20 (Box 254, Folder 3717)
  - Box 21, folder 353 (Box 254, Folder 3718)
  - Box 24 (Box 254, Folder 3719)
  - Box 28, folder 431 (Box 254, Folder 3720)
  - Box 28, folder 438 (Box 254, Folder 3721)
  - Box 54 (Box 254, Folder 3722)
  - Box 61, folders 849-851 (Box 254, Folder 3723)
  - Box 69, folders 957-959 (Box 254, Folder 3724)
  - Box 71, folder 983 (Box 254, Folder 3725)
  - Box 91, folder 1274 (Box 254, Folder 3726)
  - Box 116, folder 1669 (Box 254, Folder 3727)
  - Box 140, folders 2228-2231 (Box 254, Folder 3728-3729)
  - Box 141, folders 2241-2242 (Box 254, Folder 3730)
  - Box 162, folder 2583 (Box 254, Folder 3731)
  - Box 162, folder 2584 (Box 254, Folder 3732)
  - Box 162, folder 2585 (Box 254, Folder 3733)
  - Box 162, folder 2586 (Box 254, Folder 3734)
  - Box 190 (Box 255, Folder 3735)
  - Box 207 (Box 256, Folder 3743-3746)
  - Box 208 (Box 256, Folder 3747)
  - Box 213 (Box 256, Folder 3748-3753)
  - Box 214 (Box 256, Folder 3754-3756)
  - Box 215 (Box 256, Folder 3757-3758)
  - Boxes 215-217 (Box 256, Folder 3759-3762)
  - Boxes 218-220 (Box 256, Folder 3763-3765)
  - Box 220 (Box 257, Folder 3766-3767)
  - Box 221 (Box 257, Folder 3768-3770)
  - Box 222 (Box 257, Folder 3771-3774)
  - Box 97 (Box 261, Folder 3791-3799)
- Restricted Fragile Oversize Papers
  - Boxes 34 and 37 (Box 258, Folder 3775)
  - Boxes 48-49 and 52-56 (Box 258, Folder 3776)
  - Box 71, folder 975 (Box 258, Folder 3777)
  - Boxes 215-217 (Box 259, Folder 3778-3782)
  - Boxes 218-220 (Box 260, Folder 3783-3790)